Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers International Union, AFL-CIO, Local 155 Records 1984.0011
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers International Union, AFL-CIO, Local 155 Records
1892-1982
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1984.0011
3 Linear Feet
Originally chartered in 1892 as Local 155 of the Journeymen Bakers and Confectioners International Union located in Waterbury Connecticut. In 1904, the name was changed to Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union. In 1978, the union merged with Tobacco Workers Union to create the present union. Each time the international name changed the local received a new charter. The Local history can be found in Series IV.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The records were deposited by the Local 155 president, Ron Napoli in April 1984.
Arrangement
Series I: Charters (1892-1969) includes the original charter and subsequent updates reflecting the growth and development of the union.
Series II: Minutes (1921-1977) contains the minutes of the regular membership and special meetings of the local.
Series III: Agreements (1932-1977) includes contracts between Local 155 and several baking companies in the Waterbury area.
Series IV: History (pre-1900, 1982)contains a history of the union prepared by Michael Camorata, Chief Trustee of the Executive Board, and James Pittman, Vice President and Financial Secretary, in 1982, celebrating "90 Years of Bakers in Waterbury." Also included is a rules and regulations flyer.
History
The local was originally chartered on 19 July 1892 as Local 155 of the Journeymen Bakers and Confectioners International Union. In 1904, the name of the international was changed to the Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union. In 1978, the union merged with the Tobacco Workers Union to form the Bakery, Confectionery and Tobacco Workers International Union. When the international changed its name the local received a new charter.
Local 155 is located in Waterbury, Connecticut, home of more bakeries per capita than any other town in the state.
A more detailed history of Local 155 is located in Series IV, "90 years of Bakers in Waterbury, 1892-1982" by Michael Camorata and James Pittman.
Scope and Content
This is a small collection of minutes, charters, agreements and related publications pertaining to the union and its activities in Connecticut.
Charters; Administrative records; Bakeries; Minutes (administrative records); Bakers; Histories; Connecticut (state); Bakery employees; Confectioners; Labor unions; Collective labor agreements; Regulations (executive records); Waterbury (Conn.); Journeymen Bakers' and Confectioners' International Union. Local 155 (Waterbury, Conn.); Journeymen Bakers' and Confectioners' International Union. Local 155 (Waterbury, Conn.); Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Local 155 (Waterbury, Conn.)
- Series I: Charters, 1892-1969
  - 1892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1898 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Minutes, 1921-1977
  - 1921-1977, (3 volumes) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series III: Agreements, 1932-1977
  - General Baking Company, 1933-1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mohican Baking Company, 1932-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Reymond Baking Company, 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Schneider Baking Company, 1932-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series IV: History, pre-1900, 1982
  - "90 Years of Bakers in Waterbury, 1892-1982" (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "Rules and "Regulations", pre-1900 (Box 1)